Hi and welcome to the Vacation Labs booking engine. This video will take you through the process of
creating a product which could be your tour, trip or an activity.
You can create a new tour by clicking on the new trip button on your dashboard
or the one in your product section.
which gives you an option choose the type of product you wish to create.
But, first let’s understand, that how would you categorize your product into the given options.
Any tour or activity which will last only a couple of hours or less than a day will fall under the category of Short Tours. For example
a 3 hrs walking tour in Old Delhi or a day sightseeing tour in Mumbai.
Activities like paragliding, Jet Ski rides, Bunjee Jumping etc which last only a couple of minutes will also come under the same section.
In the Multi Day Tour category you can add tours which last for more than one day.
This can be a weekend getaway of 2-3 days or a tour package of 10-12 days or more. For example the famous Golden Triangle tours
which usually lasts 2-3 days and cover Delhi-Agra and Jaipur sightseeing,
or a complete South India Tour package of 6-7 days.
they all will come under the category of multi day tour.
A class or a certification course on the other hand
would be a recurring program of short duration with fixed dates and schedules. Like a Guitar Learning Class, a dance class,
Cooking class or a 3 months summer course of painting or learning software.
Let’s just start with a short tour, the assist of the shuttle
say a Delhi walking tour of 3 hours.
Begin with choosing whether the trip is shared or private.
A shared trip is basically the one in which individuals or groups, who book separately, but travel together.
While in a Private tour a person or a group travel separately, i.e. the tour
is operated exclusively for them and others will not be made part of that departure.
If you choose a Shared trip the system will allow bookings to happen till all seats in a particular timeslot are filled, but in Private trip, the booking
system will keep on taking bookings until you manually close the booking.
Give your trip a name: In our example here we can call it a Delhi Walking Tour
Give your trip a unique code which helps you identify your trip. For example if you have a list of trips with similar names like Old Delhi Food
Walk, Delhi market walk, Delhi heritage tour then you can quickly spot your trip through the unique code.
Often if the trip name is too long it may not show up completely on mobile devices or text messages
but you can immediately recognize it with the help of unique code.
Choose the duration of the trip. One of the most important things, which a customer want know about a short tour is, its duration.
A day sightseeing tour of Mumbai can be of 6 hours also and 10 hours also.
Telling your customers how long the trip will last makes it easier for them to decide.
You can also set the number of minimum and maximum participants the trip can accommodate. For example the walking tour
can have min 2 participants and maximum 10, which would mean anyone who books will be able to make a booking only if they choose 2 or
more seats.
The booking system allows you to give your customers as much information as possible,
which can include the pictures, details of the trip, what’s included in the price and what’s not etc.
All the information you provide here shows up on the Trip Details Page.
The Inclusions and exclusions though also show up on the booking form.
Let’s start with giving the overview.
A brief description about the walking tour, which lets the customer know, what to expect during the tour and what the tour is about.
For example in case of Delhi Walking tour it can something like this:
The next section is Inclusions – where you mention everything that’s included within the price of the trip.
For example, in this walking tour, the basic price includes the transport during the walk,
snacks during the trip,
tour guide etc. Let’s add that in.
Within Exclusions you specify what is not included in the price of the trip, for example
in this particular walking tour, we expect the guests to pay for their airport to hotel transfers,
travel insurance, VISA charges etc. Let’s add those as Exclusions.
With the Highlights you try to give the customer a gist of what one will experience during the trip.
This can be a list of attractions or names of famous locations or monuments to be visited during the tour.
In this tour we will be visiting the monuments like Red Fort and Jama Masjid and the famous Chandni Chowk market.
Let's add this information to the highlights
Now, as a general guideline, it’s preferable to add Inclusions, Exclusions, and Highlights as bulleted points because they are easier for your
customer to read. However, if you feel that a paragraph of text works better, then you can use that as well.
Just a note, only the overview is a mandatory field. Inclusions, exclusions, and highlights are optional.
So, for example, if the tour that you’re creating is very, very short, 15 min Jet-Ski ride, having a “Highlights”
section may not make sense for that. So, you can leave that out by un-checking this checkbox.
So, the options which you have un-checked here will not show up on the trip details page.
Last, but one of the very important parts is the pictures.
Make sure that you upload attractive pictures related to your trip, which would be visible on your trip details page along with all the other
information provided in the basic details section.
You can also add general or tour specific terms and conditions. A travel firm which deals in short tours or walking tours,
a safety disclaimer and a refund policy could be common for all the trips, thus they can come under General terms and conditions.
But things like dress code might be applicable only on those tours which include visits to religious places.
A disclaimer on eating local food and beverage would make more sense for food specific tours.
The general terms and conditions can be mentioned only once by clicking on this and the same will appear on all the tours which are
visible on the booking form, right before making the payment.
Make sure that all the information you have mentioned is correct. Once done, click on Save and Next to proceed to the next step.